## JOSEPH JOHNSON

### WEB DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

- +44 7512 610315 (UK) +66 9291 63856 (Thailand)
- joseph.johnson27001@gmail
- Chiang Mai, Thailand
- joseph-johnson27001.github .io/Website/

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- Chart.js
- VueJS
- Vuetify
- Bootstrap
- JSON
- PostgreSQL
- SASS
- Typescript
- jQuery
- Node & Yarn Package Manager
- GitHub
- Wordpress
- Elementor Page Builder

## **EDUCATION**

### Front End Tech Degree

Team Treehouse

Remote | 2020

### **Ancient History**

Royal Holloway: University of London

Surrey, UK | 2013

### **PROFILE**

An ambitious web developer, with a passion for creating clean, responsive and user-friendly websites. Along with my professional experience, I have developed a cryptocurrency tracking application, a quiz application and several other demo sites, all of which are viewable on my portfolio page. I now hope to join an exciting team where I can contribute to projects for clients, whilst continuing to broaden my programming knowledge.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### JUNIOR DEVELOPER

DIRECT BUSINESS SOLUTIONS | REMOTE | APR 2021 - JAN 2022

- Utilised 'Vue.JS' and 'Vuetify' to develop a scheduling application, with built-in reminders, timers, and notifications. This product was then used by the entire sales team to assist with the business' daily sales operation
- Linked the above scheduling application to 'Microsoft Outlook' and 'Microsoft Todo' through the use of an API
- Implemented a service worker so the above application could be used offline
- Discussed with other members of the team how best to utilise UX and UI features for the staff website
- Edited staff website based on the developed designs
- Created editable data tables, with information drawn from back end databases, utilising both PostgreSQL and VueJS
- Completed various ad hoc coding tasks, including database management fixes, editing web page styling, and re-working programming functions
- Utilised the 'liveshare' feature on 'Visual Studio Code' in order to edit code with other team members
- Installed and updated needed dependencies, using both 'Node Package Manager' and 'Yarn'
- Engaged in code reviews with other members of the team

### PERSONAL WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Built a cryptocurrency tracking webpage using multiple API's, ReactJS and Chart.js
- Created an online quiz application, using JavaScript programming, with multiple questions and categories for the viewer to choose from
- Developed a Star Wars Themed portfolio page for Darth Vader, based on designs found online
- Utilised 'Bootstrap' to create a landing page for an imitation tour company
- Developed a landing page for a "cliche" business company

## JOSEPH JOHNSON

### WFB DFVFI OPFR

# ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- ISO 27001 Lead Implementer
- ISO 27005 Risk Management
- 120 Hour TEFL Certification

## LANGUAGES

- English | Fluent
- Mandarin | Basic
- French | Basic

## **INTERESTS**

- Travel
- Music
- Football
- Photography
- Cooking
- Weightlifting
- Chess
- History
- Gaming
- Guitar
- Cryptocurrency
- Studying Mandarin

## EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

### PERSONAL WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS (CONTINUED)

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Built a mock employee directory, using JSON and an API
- Developed a mock web application dashboard utilising different interactive jQuery charts
- Built a JavaScript focused 'Star Wars' game based on the TV show, 'Wheel of Fortune'
- Used the SASS preprocessor, to develop a mock web style guide, which could then be used to help style projects
- Developed and created an online personal portfolio page using HTML & CSS,
  JavaScript, and the CSS framework 'Bootstrap', to host all of the above projects
- Completed the Team Treehouse 'Front End Web Development Techdegree' whilst receiving the highest marks of 'Exceeds Expectations' for every project
- Created multiple WordPress websites using the Divi theme, prebuilt design templates, and the 'Elementor' page builder

#### **ONLINE ENGLISH TEACHER**

ITUTORGROUP | REMOTE | AUG 2018 - APR 2021

- Provided Online English classes to Chinese and Japanese adult students
- Received an average rating of 9.8/10 across 1000+ teaching hours
- Delivered classes to all levels of students ranging from absolute beginners to students with excellent fluency
- Provided feedback to students after every lesson on where they held excelled and areas where they could improve

### **OPERATIONS ADMINISTRATOR**

CAMBRIDGE ASSESSMENT | CAMBRIDGE, UK | FEB 2018 - AUG 2018

- Assisted with the worldwide operational running of the IELTS language examination
- Worked closely with all levels of the IELTS hierarchy including students, test centres, assessment teams, and directors
- Liaised with clients, customers, and worldwide distributors
- Assisted universities and businesses with the verification of IELTS results and certifications

### **ENGLISH TEACHER**

AFFILIATED SCHOOLS OF THE BEIJING UNIVERSITY OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY  $\mid$  BEIJING, CHINA  $\mid$  FEB 2016 - JUL 2017

- Prepared and delivered English lessons to around 900 Chinese students aged 7-16
- Created bespoke lessons for each class and provided monthly reports for each student